(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
作詞：Sena Kiryuuin 作曲・編曲：Giga
Lyrics: Sena Kiryuuin / Composition & Arrangement: Giga
はーい注目　まぁいっちょ踊ってこうか？
Hey attention! Shall we dance one more time?
現役牛耳ってんのは…　あーぁーあーい
The one who's currently taking the lead is... Aye aye aye.
あれ〜？君たちの声　まだ足りてないんじゃないの〜？
Huh? Your voices aren't loud enough yet, are they?
Our night's just begun, aye let's blast it.
赤く火照る face
A red, flushed face.
ヒートアップしちゃって絡む sweat
Heating up and tangling with sweat.
渇いた喉潤す　オアシスよマリンブルー
Quench your dry throat. The oasis is Marine Blue.
あっはーん！たまらないんでしょ？
A-haan! You can't resist it, right?
ぱっきゅん♡
Pa-kyun♡
From shore to shore, my moves bring the storm to the floor
Thunder rays blast a sonic boom, I ride the beat like I'm surfing shockwaves
Don't need no sunblock, I can make it rain 'cause you hit the jackpot
Baby, get ready, if you wanna ride on with the OGs
アーッチチな二人はだぁれ？
Who are the two who are smoking hot?
Hands up ぶち上げたまえ！
Hands up, let's turn it up!
クラッときちゃう様な熱が足りない
I need more heat, the kind that makes you feel dizzy.
Our night's just begun, aye let's blast it.
ハジけて派手にいったーれ！
Burst out and go wild!
(Yeah baby!) 来世まで we wanna party
(Yeah baby!) We wanna party until our next life.
All eyes on me, I can taste the high
Aye まだまだ沸いてこうぜ
Aye, let's keep things boiling.
はーい注目　まぁいっちょ踊ってこうか？
Hey attention! Shall we dance one more time?
現役牛耳ってんのは…　あーぁーあーい
The one who's currently taking the lead is... Aye aye aye.
え・い・う・あー
E-I-U-Ah
よそ見しちゃやーん　マリンが bestest girl じゃん？
Don't look away. Marine is the bestest girl, isn't she?
砂の数よりも魅力がある　君たちもう　ねぇ、虜でしょ？
I have more charms than the grains of sand. You're already captivated, aren't you?
「お年の数程」って誰が言った？
Who said 'as many as her age'?
大人の魅力よ
It's adult charm.
ておいコラァ！
Hey, hold on!
マリンは17さい♡
Marine is 17 years old♡
っておい聞けや！！
Hey, listen to me!!
我慢の限界かな　とかってきゃあ！
Maybe I'm at my limit... or something like that, kyaa!
Bring in the heat that can't be splashed away (Hiiya!)
Fishing a big catch, the stardom I deserve
But I'm just chilling, a mocktail, Maitai sipping
'Cause I got that juice
Might let you have a taste
みてこの Body Money でしょ、Honey
Look at this body. It's money, isn't it, honey?
秘宝な素肌ね
Treasure-like bare skin.
やん見ないで、待って
Oh, don't look... wait.
Beside a bonfire, our luring smoke takes you higher
ねぇ We drive you crazy
Hey, we drive you crazy.
Ahoy!
あはは　熱苦しくなってこう
Ahaha, let's get even hotter.
もうどうしようもない　My bright spotlight
There's no stopping it now. My bright spotlight.
どんどん新境地いっちゃいそ？ (Oh baby!)
Are we heading into new territory? (Oh baby!)
アーッチチな二人はだぁれ？
Who are the two who are smoking hot?
Hands up ぶち上げたまえ！
Hands up, let's turn it up!
クラッときちゃう様な熱が足りない
I need more heat, the kind that makes you feel dizzy.
Our night's just begun, aye let's blast it.
ハジけて派手にいったーれ！ (Yeah baby!)
Burst out and go wild! (Yeah baby!)
来世まで we wanna party
We wanna party until our next life.
(Oh baby!)
All eyes on me I can taste the fire
Aye まだまだ沸いてこうぜ
Aye, let's keep it heating up!
はーい注目 まぁいっちょ踊ってこうか？
Attention everyone! Shall we dance one more time?
仙狐牛耳ってんのは…
The one ruling over the Senko...
Bring it back! One last time!
アタシたちマジで最強じゃん？
Aren't we seriously the strongest?
Just two besties so fly! Ah-ah-ah.
Overdose
作詞・作曲・編曲：なとり
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: natori
本当は分かっていた
いけないことだったって、分かっていたのに
In truth, I knew.
I knew it was something I shouldn't do, and yet...
この手をすり抜ける全部が愛に見えたの
Everything that slipped through my hands looked like love.
確かめていた言葉が形になって、揺れるだけ
The words I was confirming just take shape and sway.
弾いて、描いて きっと、それだけ
Plucking, drawing, surely that's all.
つまらない正解の読み合わせ
Comparing boring correct answers.
あとちょっとで分かりかけていたのに
I was just about to understand.
飲んで、吐いて 全部忘れちゃえ
Drink, vomit, and forget it all.
Overdose 君とふたり やるせない日々
Overdose, just the two of us, these helpless days.
解像度の悪い夢を見たい
I want to see a low-resolution dream.
Overdose 君とふたり 甘いハッタリ
Overdose, just the two of us, a sweet bluff.
Don't stop it music, darling
本当に分かっている？
いけないことだったって、分かっている？
Do you really understand?
Do you understand it was something we shouldn't do?
多分、時間だけが過ぎていく 問答で満ちていく
Probably only time passes, filling up with questions.
言い訳する間もなく、裸になってしまうだけ
Without time for excuses, I just end up exposed.
きっと、溜まっていくんだ ずっと
Surely, it'll keep piling up, forever.
終わってしまえばいいと、ふっと
Suddenly wishing it would all just end.
あの甘い果実のように僕ら、壊れていく
Like that sweet fruit, we're breaking down.
踊って、眠って 全部忘れちゃえ
Dance, sleep, and forget it all.
Overdose 君とふたり 分かりたいのに
Overdose, just the two of us, I want to understand you, but...
変に間の悪い嘘が嫌い
I hate lies with strangely bad timing.
Overdose 君とふたり 分かりたいのに
Overdose, just the two of us, I want to understand you, but...
Two step from hell with me, darling
Overdose 君とふたり やるせない日々
Overdose, just the two of us, these helpless days.
解像度の悪い夢を見たい
I want to see a low-resolution dream.
Overdose 君とふたり 甘いハッタリ
Overdose, just the two of us, a sweet bluff.
Don't stop it music, darling
Overdose 君とふたり 分からないけど
Overdose, just the two of us, I don't know but...
変に間の悪い夢でもいいから
Even a dream with strangely bad timing is fine.
Overdose 君とふたり 甘いハッタリ
Overdose, just the two of us, a sweet bluff.
Don't stop it music, darling
愛包ダンスホール 今日はボレロ
Aibo Dancehall, today is a bolero.
濁った少年 甘酸っぱい感情
Muddled boy, bittersweet feelings.
求愛人類ハイファイ・アバヨ
Courtship mankind, Hi-Fi goodbye.
オーブントースター 零れ漏れよ
Oven toaster, let it spill over.
おかわりならアルコール次第ね
If you want seconds, it depends on the alcohol.
終わらないラブコール・ダンス・デイ
Never-ending love call dance day.
愛包ダンスホール
作詞：Gohgo 作曲：涼木シンジ 編曲：涼木シンジ
Aibo Dancehall
Lyrics: Gohgo, Music: Ryoki Shinji, Arrangement: Ryoki Shinji
愛包ダンスホール
Aibo Dancehall.
おかわりならもう一回
If you want seconds, one more time.
愛包ダンスホール
Aibo Dancehall.
3.1415926535のパイだって
Even pi is 3.1415926535.
割り切れない気持ち抱えてるよ
I'm holding onto feelings that don't add up.
ロボ人も幻人も亜人もエンジニアも
エンジン組んで仲良くやれたらとか
Robot people, phantoms, demi-humans, and engineers,
if we could all just get along together...
割り切れない生命いさかいのヘブン
A divisive life, a heaven of conflict.
今夜はいいんじゃない？ ほらオエオエオエオエヨ
Isn't tonight fine? Look, woe-woe-woe-woe-yo.
踊ればいいんじゃない？ ほらブリブリブランレバ
Why not just dance? Look, shake-shake-shake-it-up.
休戦しようぜ 涙が湧泉温泉
Let's call a truce, tears are hot spring gushers.
汗ばんだらガンダーラ・サンサーラ
If you get sweaty, Gandhara Samsara.
なに言ってんだ？（自問自答）
What am I even saying? (Talking to self)
高まった感動の再会
An emotional and moving reunion.
集まった愛情のWi-Fi
A gathered Wi-Fi of affection.
持寄った常灯の人影
Shadows gathered under the eternal light.
愛してるが重なって 狂まった人類の状態
Piling up 'I love you's, the state of mankind gone mad.
熱いミートパイみたいだね
It's like a hot meat pie, isn't it?
パッパッパッパッパッパッパイ！❤
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pie!❤
愛包愛いっぱいで惚れ惚れよ
Full of Ai-pai and love, I'm enchanted
とろけだ少年 甘酸っぱいレモン
A boy who started to melt, sweet and sour lemon
Q-I-人類♥満杯だい
Q-I-Humanity♥ It's full
完敗完全に惚れ惚れよ
Total defeat, I'm completely enchanted
ミルフィーユみたいに愛踊ろう
Let's dance a love like a mille-feuille
頭ん中パッパッパッパッパッパッパッパ
Inside my head, it's pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
ララヤカなロラノロなロラノロなロラノロなジャンレノンも愛牌か
Lalayaka, Lalanoro, Lalanoro, Lalanoro, is John Lennon also a love pie?
イマジン・オール・ザ・ピーポーの再建
Reconstructing Imagine All The People
ダンスホールじゃ詩人もヒーロー
In the dance hall, even poets are heroes
乾杯な 今日はこれレロ
Cheers, today it's this Lelo
交わって人類 馬鹿んねって笑って
Intertwine, humanity, smile and say "How foolish"
おかわりほしいでしょ？
You want a second helping, don't you?
全人類公正舞台会の目指すべきビジョンは
The vision that all mankind's fair stage association should aim for is
レンジでチンしてパイになるような
Like something that turns into a pie when microwaved
脳みそもトロトロの世の実写をスローガンにオールナイト
All night, with the slogan of a live-action world where even brains are melting
踊りまして凡波ソサエティ
Dancing, ordinary wave society
継ぎまして聖人を量産
Next, mass-producing saints
パッパッパッパッパッパッパイ！❤
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pie!❤
人類最高のダンスタイム
Humanity's best dance time
せーの！
One, two!
愛牌ダンスホール
Ai-pai Dance Hall
アイライライ 愛牌ダンスホール
Ai-lai-lai, Ai-pai Dance Hall
愛牌ダンスホール
Ai-pai Dance Hall
僕等が生まれて初めて知る音は心臓の鼓動だろ
The first sound we ever know when we're born is the heartbeat, right?
トドントドン ダトン ダトン ダテン ダトンダ
To-don-to-don, da-ton, da-ton, da-ten, da-ton-da
それはリズムと知った
I knew that was rhythm
いにしえも いまどきも ♡BEATが僕達を包んで繋いでんだろ？
Ancient times and nowadays, ♡BEAT surrounds and connects us, doesn't it?
パッパッパッパッパッパッパイ！❤
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pie!❤
愛包愛いっぱいで惚れ惚れよ
Full of Ai-pai and love, I'm enchanted
とろけだ少年 甘酸っぱいレモン
A boy who started to melt, sweet and sour lemon
Q-I-人類♥満杯だい
Q-I-Humanity♥ It's full
完敗完全に惚れ惚れよ
Total defeat, I'm completely enchanted
ミルフィーユみたいに愛踊り
Dancing a love like a mille-feuille
頭ん中パッパッパッパッパッパッパッパ
Inside my head, it's pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
ラララララララララ
La la la la la la la la la
まるでバージンロードで踊ってるみたい
It's like dancing on a virgin road
生まれ変わったような気分でして
Feeling like I've been reborn
乾杯な 今日はこれレロ
Cheers, today it's this Lelo
交わって人類 馬鹿んねって笑っ照れ
Intertwine, humanity, smile and be shy, saying "How foolish"
てってってっ照れってってー
Te-te-te-shy-te-te-
寂しいよな 終わりは近づく時さ
It's lonely when the end draws near
終わらないで 夢の様に続けりゃいいじゃん
Don't end it, it's fine to keep it going like a dream
計算なんてできないが…！
I can't even calculate...!
愛いっぱい！
Full of love!
愛牌ダンスホール 今日はこれレロ
Ai-pai Dance Hall, today it's this Lelo
とろけだ少年 甘酸っぱい感情
A boy who started to melt, sweet and sour feelings
Q-I-人類♥満杯さ
Q-I-Humanity♥ It's full
また食べに来てね
Please come back to eat again
あなたならいつでもいいよ
With you, it's fine anytime
おかわりほしいでしょ？
You want a second helping, don't you?
せーの！
One, two!
愛牌ダンスホール
Ai-pai Dance Hall
おかわりならばほしい
If it's a second helping, I want it
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
愛牌ダンスホール
Ai-pai Dance Hall
どうぞ
There you go
め組のひと
Megumi no Hito
いなせだね 夏を連れて来た女
How stylish, the woman who brought the summer
渚まで噂走るよ めッ！
The rumors run all the way to the beach! Me!
涼しげな目もと流し目 eye eye eye
Cool eyes, a sidelong glance, eye eye eye
粋な事件 起こりそうだぜ めッ！
It feels like a stylish incident is about to happen! Me!
妖しい Sweet Baby め組のひとだね
Mysterious Sweet Baby, you're a person from the Me-group
お前のニュースでビーチは突然パニック
The beach is suddenly in a panic at news of you
Baby, baby, be my girl
夢中なのさ be my girl
I'm crazy about you, be my girl
浮気の微笑みに 俺たちもそわそわ
Your flirtatious smile makes us feel restless
男たちの心 奪うたびに お前
Every time you steal the hearts of men
奪うたびに お前 綺麗になってくね
Every time you steal them, you become more beautiful
夏の罪は素敵すぎる
Summer sins are all too wonderful
いなせだね 夏を連れて来た人
How stylish, the person who brought the summer
渚まで噂走るよ めッ！
The rumors run all the way to the beach! Me!
涼しげな目もと流し目 eye eye eye
Cool eyes, a sidelong glance, eye eye eye
粋な事件 起こりそうだぜ めッ！
It feels like a stylish incident is about to happen! Me!
小粋だね 髪に飾った花も
How stylish, the flower you put in your hair
細い腰 あわせ揺れるよ めッ！
Your slender waist sways in time! Me!
ひと夏の恋を引き込む eye eye eye
A summer love that draws you in, eye eye eye
気まぐれに片目閉じるよ めッ！
Whimsically closing one eye! Me!
夏に繰り出した め組のひとだね
You're the one from Me-gumi, heading out in summer
今年はお前が 渚きってのアイドル
This year, you're the top idol of the beach
Baby, baby, be my girl
抱きしめたい be my girl
I want to hold you, be my girl
お前が微笑めば すべてが上の空
When you smile, everything else is forgotten
男たちの心 奪うたびにお前
Every time you steal men's hearts
綺麗になってくね…
You become more beautiful...
夏の罪は罪深すぎる
Summer's sins are far too deep
いなせだね 夏を連れてきた女
How gallant, the woman who brought summer
渚まで噂走るよ めッ!
The rumors race to the shore, "Me"!
涼し気な 目もと流し目 eye eye eye
A cool gaze, a sidelong glance, eye eye eye
粋な事 起こりそうだぜ めッ!
Something chic is bound to happen, "Me"!
はい！ということで！なんと、ヒメヒナさんが来てくださいました！ありがとうございます！
Yes! And so! Surprisingly, HimeHina-san has come! Thank you so much!
お邪魔してまーす！
We're visiting!
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！ということでね、もう今日はヒメヒナさんと言ったら
Thank you! Thank you! So, today, speaking of HimeHina-san,
この、アイパイドンスホールを3人で歌っちゃいました！
we sang this "I Pipe Dancehall" as a trio!
イェーイ！やったー！最高！
Yay! We did it! The best!
3人バージョンめちゃめちゃ楽しい！めっちゃ可愛くなってて、もうすごい嬉しかったんですけど。
The trio version is so much fun! It turned out so cute, I'm really happy.
船長的にお、さ、一番最初ね、この曲選んでパート分け作ったときに、
As the captain, when I first chose this song and made the part division,
もう、なんか、え、待って、マリンがノイズすぎると思って
I was like, wait, Marine is too much of a noise...
なんで！？
Why!?
めっちゃパート少なくしてたの。
I made my part so small.
そうなの！？
Is that so!?
そう。サビとか、これ全部ヒメヒナさんに歌ってほしいと思って。
Yeah. For the chorus and all, I wanted HimeHina-san to sing it all.
マリンが歌っちゃダメだと思って、自分のライブなのになぜかヒメヒナさんだらけの状態にしてたら、
I thought Marine shouldn't sing, so I made it all HimeHina-san even though it's my own live...
ヒメヒナさんサイドから、「いやこれマリンさんのパート増やしてください」みたいな
From HimeHina-san's side, they were like, "No, please increase Marine-san's parts."
主役ですから！
Because you're the star!
本当だよ！お前が少なすぎっから！
Seriously! You had too few!
いっぱい歌わせていただきました。でもすごい一緒に歌えて楽しかったです！ありがとうございました。
I got to sing a lot. But it was so much fun singing together! Thank you.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
フォーメーションもね、3人バージョンに、この日のために練習して。可愛くなりました。
The formation too, we practiced a trio version for this day. It turned out cute.
ありがとうございます！嬉しい、本当に嬉しいです。もう、生でこの歌声が聞けたことがもう感動。
Thank you! I'm happy, really happy. Hearing these voices live was moving.
こちらもです！
Us too!
本当にだよ！
Seriously!
こちらもです。そうそう、あ、めっちゃ豪華パイ。あ、どうもどうも。
Us too. Yeah, yeah, ah, such a gorgeous 'pai'. Ah, thank you, thank you.
歌って踊ってもらっても最高ですよ！
It's the best having you sing and dance!
ありがとうございます。もう一曲が、め組のひと、なんですけど、これなんで選んだと思いますか？
Thank you. The other song was "Me-gumi no Hito," but why do you think I chose it?
え、なんで？
Eh, why?
えー、ヒメちゃん、お歌が、こう、歌謡曲が好きだから、みたいな？
Eh, because Hime-chan likes, like, Showa-era pop songs?
うん、そう。そうなんですけど。
Yeah, that's true.
あの、この「め組のひと」って、あの倖田來未さんのバージョンがあるんですけど、
You know, for "Me-gumi no Hito," there's a Koda Kumi version...
おお、おお、おお。
Oh, oh, oh.
ま、今日この、そのキーなんですけど。なんか、そのキー聞いてるときにね、
Well, today we used that key. While listening to that key, I thought,
「あ、これヒメヒナさん、むっちゃ合う！」これって。
"Ah, this fits HimeHina-san perfectly!"
本当！？
Really!?
「これもう半分倖田來未やん」と思って。
I thought, "This is basically half Koda Kumi already."
恐れ多いよ！恐れ多いよ！絶対合うと思って。3人で歌ったら熱いかなと思って選ばせていただきました！
That's too much praise! I thought it would definitely fit. I chose it thinking it would be hot as a trio!
めちゃめちゃ楽しかった！歌いやすかったんじゃないですか？めっちゃ合ってたから。
It was so much fun! Wasn't it easy to sing? Because it fit so well.
めちゃめちゃいい。そうですよね、もう、めっちゃ声シナジーあって、歌いやすかっただろうなと思って。
It's so good. Right, the vocal synergy was amazing, I thought it must have been easy to sing.
もうすごい美声だったんで、何回もね、繰り返し聴いていただきたいなと思います。
It was such a beautiful voice, I hope everyone listens to it over and over.
ぜひ！ヒナも聴こ。
By all means! Hina will listen too.
地味に、今日、初絡みなんです。我々。
Quietly, today is actually our first time interacting. Us.
そうなんですー！
That's right!
実は。ちょっと、あの、時系列的に、もう、あの、お邪魔してるヒメヒナさんチャンネルにお邪魔した後になってるんですけど。
Actually. Chronologically, this is after I've already visited the HimeHina channel as a guest...
でも、ここが初絡みなんですよね！
But *this* is our first interaction!
初めまして！初めまして！時系列的には初めまして！
Nice to meet you! Nice to meet you! Chronologically, nice to meet you!
もうなんか、すごい、全然、もう全然まだドキドキモードが抜けてなくて。すみません。
It's like, really, the nervous mode hasn't left me yet. Sorry.
なんかさっき「お前」って感じで来てほしいって言われたけど、いけないいけない。
Earlier I was told to act like "Hey you (omae)", but I can't, I can't.
ちょっと、行くには、もうちょっと、なんかウザ絡みしてくれないと。
To go there, I need you to, like, bother me a bit more.
ウザ絡み？なんか、いい人すぎて、「お前」ってならない！
Bother you? You're too nice, we can't say "Hey you"!
パッパッパンチ！やるか！？やるかてめえ！
Pa-pa-punch! You wanna go!? You wanna go, you!
一生懸命！一生懸命！無理して戦ってますが。
Doing our best! Doing our best! We're struggling to fight, but.
いや、ありがとうございます。これからもぜひ、一緒に歌ったりなんだりかんだり。
No, thank you. From now on, let's definitely sing together and do various things.
そうだ、そうだ！本当にコラボしたいな！しましょう！
Right, right! I really want to collab! Let's do it!
あとさ、動画でなんかやりたい！
Also, I want to do something in a video!
やりましょうよ！大好きだから！オリジナル曲も超好き！
Let's do it! Because I love you guys! I love the original songs too!
え、ありがとうございます。いっぱい聴いてるよ。え、ちょっと待って、
Eh, thank you. I listen to them a lot. Eh, wait a minute,
でもマリンがここに挟まったら処刑されちゃうって。なんで！
but if Marine gets sandwiched here, I'll be executed. Why!
挟む、挟む。待って、もう顔のデカさが、ちょっと、もう引いて引いて。
Sandwich, sandwich. Wait, my face size is, just, pull back, pull back.
イェーイ！フレームみたいになってる我々。ヒメヒナフレーム！
Yay! We're like a frame. HimeHina frame!
あ、可愛い！最高最高！ありがとうございます！スクショ、スクショ撮って！
Ah, cute! The best! Thank you! Screenshot, take a screenshot!
あ、撮ってください。いい感じ、超可愛い！
Ah, please take one. It's looking good, so cute!
マリン！あ、カメラのアングルすごい！いい！あ、もう時間だ。
Marine! Ah, the camera angle is amazing! Good! Ah, it's time.
それでは次の曲、いきたいと思います！
Now, I'd like to move on to the next song!
いきますよー！
Here we go!
出航ー！
Set sail!
ヨーソロー！
Aye aye!
はい、完璧！
Yes, perfect!
やったー、できたー！
Yay, we did it!
間違えなかった！
I didn't make a mistake!
間違えるな！
Don't make mistakes!
いつか観ていた映画の中みたい
Like a scene from a movie I once saw
工事中の駅前 空へ背伸びしていくビルディング
In front of the station under construction,
buildings stretching towards the sky
ヒールが鳴らすリズムと命の音が揃う
The rhythm of my heels matches the sound of life
あたしはまだ未完成で不完全
I am still unfinished and incomplete
起死回生のハウツー知ってるの
I know the how-to for a miraculous comeback
今が一番若いの 第六感、六感またがって
I'm the youngest right now, straddling my
sixth sense, my sixth sense
今日は年甲斐ないことしたいの
Today, I want to do something not act my age
予定にないこと 第六感、六感教えて
Something unplanned, sixth sense, tell me
物足りないの 引き合いたいよ 偶然とハートしたい
It's not enough, I want to be drawn to you,
I want to have a heart with coincidence
さぁおいでませ 旋律 誰彼 I got it
Come one, come all, melody, whoever, I got it
道連れ世は情け I got it
In this world of traveling companions, there is
kindness, I got it
ご覧じませ この手立て
Witness this method
弱さ凌ぐ一手工にあり
There's a clever move to overcome weakness
いつか話した予想とは違っているものさ
It's different from the prediction we once talked
about
そんな悲しまないでいいよ
You don't have to be so sad
今が一番早いの 第六感、六感あやかかって
I'm the fastest right now, benefiting from
my sixth sense, my sixth sense
疾走るハート嘘はつけないよ
I can't lie to my racing heart
台詞にない言葉 交換、交換おしえて
Exchange words not in the script, tell me, tell me
そうくだらないを言い合いたい 特別を感じたい
I want to say silly things to each other, I want
to feel special
産声をあげた日は理由もなく泣いていたのに
On the day I was born, I was crying for no reason
今僕ら泣くことすら上手くできずに
Now we can't even cry well
されどしかと死守せよ 品格と真似できぬプライドを
But firmly protect your dignity and incomparable
pride
せーので手放せよ 感覚で胸を打つものそれ以外を
On the count of three, let go of everything except
what strikes your heart by intuition
Crazy about this thing
今が一番若いの 第六感、六感またがって
I'm the youngest right now, straddling my
sixth sense, my sixth sense
今日は年甲斐ないことしたいの
Today, I want to do something not act my age
予定にないこと 第六感、六感教えて おしえて おしえて
Something unplanned, sixth sense, tell me, tell me,
tell me
今最高潮なんです 第六感、六感またがって
I'm at my peak right now, straddling my
sixth sense, my sixth sense
このまま何処までいけるの
How far can we go like this?
途方も無いままで 第六感、六感おしえて
While being immense, sixth sense, tell me
もう揺るがないこの速度は そう偶然とハートしたい
This speed is no longer wavering, yes, I want to
have a heart with coincidence
魅惑を隠す箱 秘宝に香る危なげな
A box that hides fascination, a dangerous scent
in the treasure
Dangerous Marine Smell
I'm Your Treasure Box
Ahoy!
これ開けたら君たちになんて言ってあげるべきかなあ...？
If I open this, what should I say to you...?
探してたのは歌手の『お・ん・な』でしょ？
What you were looking for was the "woman" of the
singer, right?
ああん そんなにかっついちゃダメだゾ♡かな？
Ah, "Don't be so greedy♡", maybe?
お宝より魅力的な"モノ"見つけちゃった...？ いいじゃない♡
Did you find something more attractive than
treasure...? That's nice♡
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝 それは私
The inviting garnet red, the finest pirate
treasure, that is me
嘘が溢れ漂う香りをどうか怖がらないで 開けてみて
Please don't be afraid of the scent of overflowing
lies, try opening it
アッハッハッハ...
A-hahahahaha...
Sexy世界一 Superピチピチ
Sexy world's number one, Super fresh/bouncy
ぶっちゃけ船長捕まえたくない？
Honestly, don't you want to catch the captain?
You're gonna get the treasure Maybe tasting me
私の甘さが欲しいでしょ
You want my sweetness, don't you?
(Ah-hoy!! DA-BA-DIA-BOX)
秘宝の鍵を
The key to the treasure
優しく刺して
Gently insert it
真紅の扉
The crimson door
マジで手ぇ開けて
Seriously, open it up
Ahoy♥
じれったい貴方の手 海図にこぼす甘い溜息のTease
Your frustrating hand, a sweet sigh of a tease spilled on the chart
純紅のバラがしおれる前に
Before the pure crimson rose withers
WE WILL SAIL THE SEVEN SEAS
(七つの大海を)
(Across the seven seas)
SUMMER SUN SMILING WITH GLEE
(股にかけ進め)
(Stride forward across the world)
SHINING OCEAN OF MARINE
(宝ってワードからなに想像してんの)
(What are you imagining from the word "treasure"?)
NOW PLEASE GRANT MY DEAREST DREAM
OPEN UP THIS BOX
OPEN IT RIGHT NOW OR I WILL SCREAM
(さもなくば)
(Or else)
AAAAAAAAAAAAAA!!!!!! (開けろおおおおおお！)
AAAAAAAAAAAAAA!!!!!! (OPEN IT!!!!!!)
泣く子も黙るNaughty悩殺ビーム キミたちもう我慢できなくない？
The naughty killer beam that silences crying children, can't you all take it anymore?
(KABOOM...)
You're gonna own the pleasure Maybe love of me?
私の全てを手に入れて
Take all of me
(Ah-hoy!! DA-BA-DIA-BOX)
金銀財宝
Gold and silver treasures
はした金でしょ
It's just pocket change, right?
しわしわになっちゃう
I'm gonna get all wrinkly
誰か助けて
Somebody help me
マジで遠慮しすぎ キミたち何考えてんの
Seriously, you're being too reserved, what are you all thinking?
分かってるんだわ渇望
I know your craving
だから今すぐ開けてよ
So open it up right now
宝箱
Treasure box
貴方を待つガーネット...
The garnet waiting for you...
(キミ...キミたち...開けて~!!)
(You... you all... open it~!!)
はぁ〜い、れをる、あ、待って、違う、歌手の女、歌手の女、歌手の女です！
Hiii, Reol, oh wait, no, the female singer, female singer, it's the female singer!
歌手の女です。
I'm the female singer.
歌手の女ありがとうございます！
Thank you, female singer!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがと、そうなんです今日誕生日なんです、はい。
Thank you, that's right, it's my birthday today, yes.
え？
Eh?
おい虚無を生むなよ。
Hey, don't create a void.
違う、なんか想定ではれをるからこう誕生日トークが来るはずだった。
No, like, I expected some birthday talk from Reol.
あ、なるほど。でもお誕生日については触れられなくないですか？
Oh, I see. But isn't it impossible not to mention the birthday?
え、なぜですか？触れてくださいよ全然。
Eh, why? Please mention it anytime.
いくつになったんですか？
How old did you turn?
あ、そこですか？もちろん17歳5周、6周、5周、4周、どっちだ、5から6周の間です。
Oh, that? Of course, the 5th, 6th, 5th, 4th round of being 17... which one... it's between 5 and 6 rounds.
なるほど。
I see.
はい。あまり計算はしないで貰ったほうがいいので、一応ね。
Yes. It's better if you don't calculate it too much, just in case.
この歌手の女とマリンはね、何年、どれぐらい、何年ぐらいですかね？
Between this female singer and Marine... how many years... how many years has it been?
3年前ぐらい？3、4年前ぐらい？
About 3 years? About 3 or 4 years ago?
3、4年前ぐらいってことに。え、なに？あ、関係値？
So it's about 3 or 4 years ago. Eh, what? Oh, our relationship?
あ、関係値関係値。
Yeah, our relationship.
関係値は、までもね、あの海賊のコスプレをなさり始めたぐらいからじゃないですか？
Relationship-wise, well, wasn't it around the time you started doing pirate cosplay?
あ、そうです、海賊のコスプレをし始めたこともありましたが、
Ah, that's right, there was a time I started doing pirate cosplay, but...
ね、今やこんな大きな船に。
Right, and now on such a big ship.
ええ、そう、ま、これちょっと今日レンタル船というか。
Yeah, well, this is kind of a rental ship today.
リースなんだ。
It's a lease.
基本自分の船持ってないので。夢を見せていけよ、おい。
I basically don't own my own ship. Let them dream, hey!
誕生日ぐらい、誕生日ぐらい。あ、一応でも今日この船貰った設定なんで。
On my birthday... at least on my birthday. Oh, for today, the setting is that I received this ship.
あ、ね、誕生日プレゼント。あ、素敵素敵。
Ah, I see, a birthday present. Oh, how lovely.
ありがとうございます、そんな場所に呼んでいただいて。ありがとうございます。
Thank you for inviting me to such a place. Thank you very much.
今日ね、この2曲歌ったんですけれど、ちょっとね、何歌うか一緒に色々考えて。
We sang these two songs today, but we thought about what to sing together.
なんかマリンの持ち歌とれをるの持ち歌をそれぞれ歌いたいよねって話になり。
We talked about wanting to sing each of Marine's and Reol's original songs.
で、マリ箱選んだのは、もう絶対れをるのこの歌手の女勢としての。
And the reason I chose "MariBako" was strictly from Reol's position as part of the female singers.
歌手の女ですぜとしての。
As someone from the female singers group.
歌手の女勢。そう、この歌唱力を見せつけるには絶対にこれがいいと思って選んだんですが、結果超いいと。
Female singers group. Right, I chose this because I thought it was perfect to show off this vocal ability, and the result was great.
なんかマリンが処刑される羽目になっちゃった...
Somehow, Marine ended up being executed...
いやいやいや、すごかった、素晴らしかった
No, no, no, it was amazing, it was wonderful.
やっぱりこれ... あそこもうセクシー。ありがとう、
As expected... that part was so sexy. Thank you,
ありがとうございます。セクシーにやっていただいて。ありがとうございます。
thank you so much. Thank you for doing it so sexily. Thank you.
でね、第六感をね、選ばせていただきましたが、
So, I chose 'Dairokkan',
元々ね、あの、おちんと悩んだんだよね。
but originally, I was torn between that and 'Ochin'.
そう、ギガンティックを歌ってほしいっていうオーダーを私はしたんですけど
Right, I actually requested for you to sing 'Gigantic',
そう、Reolが歌ってほしいって言って、
Yeah, Reol said she wanted me to sing it,
やっぱりマリンはおちんですってふくらんじゃったやばおぴんこ...
and I thought, 'Marine is all about Ochin after all', and I got all excited...
おっと。歌うか、歌ってくれるのか...
Whoops. Are we singing? Are you going to sing for us...?
って思ったけど、でもなんかやっぱり歌手の女のこの歌唱力全としたところを
I thought about it, but then I felt that to show off a female singer's
見せるなら第六感かなーと思って
full vocal prowess, 'Dairokkan' would be better.
そうですね、結局そっちになったんですね。ありがとうございます。
True, we ended up with that one. Thank you.
プロモーションビデオかっこよかったなと思います
I thought the music video was really cool.
今日ちょっと、あの、一味... あ、衣装が一味っぽさ...
Today, I'm... my outfit has a bit of an Ichimi feel...
一味っぽさっていうか、あの、まあ、あれ... 衣装、衣装ね。
Not exactly an Ichimi feel, but, well... the outfit, you know.
マリン船長の部かっぽさ。青い、あの青いんですけど...
Like one of Captain Marine's subordinates. It's blue, though...
あーじゃね、あーじゃねーよ。あのすいませんけど。
Not 'ah'! It's not 'ah'! Excuse me,
部かっぽさとか言って何も、何も部かっぽくないし。
but it doesn't look like a subordinate's outfit at all.
青いし、青いです
And it's blue. Very blue.
いやいや、ちょっと後でサイリウムを買います。赤、
No, no, I'll buy a glowstick later. Red,
イメージカラー。赤ね。赤、赤、赤。すいません
the theme color. Red. Red, red, red. My apologies.
まあまあまあ、でもね、すごい楽しかったですね。
Well, well, well, but anyway, it was really fun.
いや楽しかった、ありがとうございました
Yeah, it was fun. Thank you very much.
またぜひ機会があったら一緒に歌いたいなと...
I'd definitely love to sing with you again if there's a chance...
いや、もうこちらこそ。ええ、今度は私の船にも
The pleasure is all mine. Yes, next time, come on my ship too.
お、まじで。呼ばれる？
Oh, really? I'm invited?
大丈夫かな。今から... 今からお金貯めます。
Is it okay? I'll start... I'll start saving money now.
お前もレンタルすんのかよ
You're going to rent it too?
貸してやろうか、このレンタル船をレンタルしてやろうか
Shall I lend it to you? Shall I let you rent this rental ship?
いいんですか、いいんですか
Is that okay? Really?
はい、ということでね、じゃあそんな感じで、
All right then, moving on,
まだまだね、生誕祭続いていきますのでちょっと応援よろしくお願いしますよ
the birthday celebration is still going, so please continue to support us!
楽しんでってください。コメントしろよな。
Please enjoy the rest. Leave some comments, okay?
なんか急に... コメントしてくれよな...
Whoa, suddenly... 'Leave some comments, okay?'
何、何、どこ目線なの？
Wait, what's with that tone?
部下、部下目線、部下目線としてやっぱり。
As a subordinate, of course. From a subordinate's perspective.
はい、一緒に一味のみなさんも盛り上げてください。
Yes, everyone in Ichimi, please join in and get excited with us.
それでは、次の曲いってみ、いきましょう！
Now then, let's move on to the next song!
大丈夫か、大丈夫か...
Are you ready? Are you ready...?
中火ー！
Medium heat!
よーそろー！
Yosoro!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない
I won't let any romance scandals slide
消してあげる
I'll make them disappear
宣誓！私が大統領になったら、
Oath! When I become the president,
人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします！
women who flirt with other people's men will be exiled!
宣誓！私が大統領になったら、
Oath! When I become the president,
いやただの友達だよってごまかす奴はへそから電気を流します！
those who say 'we're just friends' as an excuse will get electrocuted through their belly buttons!
だ・だ・だ・大統領 センセーショナルクロースアップ
P-P-P-President sensational close-up
D・D・D・Don't cry やるぜ徹底的にリサーチだ
D-D-D-Don't cry I'll do some thorough research
大嫌い？しょうがない？
Hate it? Can't be helped?
クズは病気ね バイ・バイ・バイ
Trash is a disease, bye-bye-bye
権力！財産！地位！名誉！
Power! Property! Status! Honor!
なんにもないけど裁きたいでしょ？
You have nothing, but you want to judge, right?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったらね
When I become the P-P-P-President,
まずは君を捕まえるね
the first thing I'll do is catch you
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything with a wet towel
(ね・ね・ね)
(Right, right, right)
誰ですかあの女 (いやぁ〜ん)
Who is that woman? (Oh no!)
ダメですかそうですか (あっちゃ〜)
It's no good? I see. (Oops!)
ロマンスの不祥事 逃がさない
I won't let any romance scandals slide
消してあげる
I'll make them disappear
シル・ヴ・プレジデント
S'il vous plaît, President
宣誓！私が大統領になったら、
Oath! When I become the president,
ただの仕事の付き合いだよって言う奴は二度と働けなくしてやります！
those who say 'it's just a work acquaintance' will never be able to work again!
宣誓！以下略！
Oath! Etcetera!
いや向こうが強引でさっていう男の口にはレジンを流し込んで固めてやります！
men who say 'she was being pushy' will have resin poured into their mouths to seal them shut!
密・密・密着 まるでドン・ファン気取りスキャンダラス
Close, close, close contact like a scandalous Don Juan wanna-be
ま・ま・ま・末端価格 甲斐性なしのスクープね
S-S-S-Street value it's a scoop on a good-for-nothing
愛はない？理由じゃない？
No love? Not a reason?
悪くないのね ハイ・ハイ・ハイ
It's not bad, right? High, high, high
捏造の脳のいけしゃあしゃあ！
Shameless fabricated brain!
なんにもないとかありえないでしょ？
It's impossible to have nothing, right?
だ・だ・だ・大統領になってもね
Even if I become the P-P-P-President,
たぶん君は変わらないね
you probably won't change
しらっととぼけて のらりくらりかわすのね
Feigning ignorance and dodging me non-committally
(ね・ね・ね)
(Right, right, right)
デートですかこんばんは (うわぁ〜ん)
Are you on a date? Good evening. (Waah!)
本気ですかそうですか (はるお〜)
Are you serious? I see. (Haruo!)
情熱とは不注意 秘め事も
Passion is carelessness even secrets
消してしまいたい
I want to erase them
だ・だ・だ・大統領になったら
When I become the P-P-P-President,
マジで君を捕まえるね
I'll definitely catch you
濡れたタオルで 洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you spill everything with a wet towel
(ね・ね・ね)
(Right, right, right)
どこですか今あんた (いやぁ〜ん)
Where are you now? (Oh no!)
見っけちゃったバレちゃった (なお〜ん)
I found you, I caught you (Naon!)
夜道にはご用心 さよなら 代わりに銃声
Be careful on the night roads, goodbye instead of a gunshot
夜道にはご用心 さよなら 終わりに銃声
Be careful on the night roads. Goodbye, a gunshot at the end.
しる・ゔ・ぷれぷれ ぷれぜでんと
Sil-vou-pre-pre President
しる・ゔ・ぷれぷれ ぷれぜでゅあ
Sil-vou-pre-pre Presidua
ドキ・ドキ・して Rouge?
Does your heart throb, Rouge?
いきまーすよー！
Here we go!
(無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！)
(Innocent! Innocent! Pretty girl innocent!)
(マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！)
(Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!)
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
As expected, sparkling, more dizzy
ねえ、言ったよね？年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Hey, you said it, right? That age doesn't matter.
そう言うめんどくさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
That you'd love me including those annoying parts.
ねえねえ、言ったよね？言ってない？ふーんそういうこというんだ。
Hey, hey, you said it, right? You didn't? Hmmm, so that's how it is.
ちなみにこのフレでは美少女無罪が適用されますけど！
By the way, in this phrase, 'pretty girl innocent' applies!
まかせて魔法で若返り (若返り！)
Leave it to me, rejuvenating with magic (Rejuvenating!)
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけ (キミにだけ！)
The secret true face is only for you (Only for you!)
【特別ですよ～！】
It's special~!
Ah... アタシ厄介よ
Ah... I'm a handful
Ah... 港なんかじゃ
Ah... in a port or something
はしゃげないわ 近頃はね
I can't frolic lately
宝の島にしてほしい気分 (出航!!)
I feel like making it a treasure island (Set sail!!)
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, pretty girl innocent
キミの一番目指してヨーソロー！
Aiming to be your number one, steady as she goes!
本当は自信ないけど頑張っちゃう (わっふーい！)
Actually I have no confidence but I'll do my best (Wahoo!)
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun kyu kyu kyurun-run
恋する気持ち17歳
Feelings of love, 17 years old
0時(テッペン)になっちゃう オトナの時間
It's becoming midnight, adult time
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
As expected, sparkling, more dizzy
ドキ・ドキ・して Rouge? まだ早い♡
Does your heart throb, Rouge? It's still too early♡
だっ だっ ダメですか？フリルの服着たら (そんなことないぜ！)
Is- is- is it no good? If I wear frilly clothes (That's not true!)
だっ だっ だって 魔法少女になってみたい (ギリギリ有罪!?)
But, but, because I want to try becoming a magical girl (Barely guilty!?)
進路はなんなん星 ちょっぴり難解な積極性？
Course is 'What' star, a slightly difficult aggressiveness?
結局キミももっと若い子？
In the end, do you also like younger girls?
なんでもするから 見捨てないでキミたち！ (ちょっとイイトコ見てみたーい！)
I'll do anything, so don't abandon me you guys! (I want to see a bit of a good side!)
Ah... たまにいじけちゃう
Ah... sometimes I get sulky
Ah... それでもいいの？
Ah... is that still okay?
年頃だもん 本気にしちゃう
It's that age, I'll take it seriously
嵐の中も 一緒に行こう (出航!!)
Even in the storm, let's go together (Set sail!!)
ハートにチャーム 美少女無罪
Charm in the heart, pretty girl innocent
あれあれどーした？ めんどくさいよなんて言っちゃって
Oh my, what's wrong? Saying things like it's a pain
かまってくれるキミが好き (Ahoy!!)
I like you for looking after me (Ahoy!!)
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun kyu kyu kyurun-run
優しくしてね17歳
Please be kind, 17 years old
突っ込んで正解 お楽しみ中♡
Correct to dive in, enjoying ourselves♡
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
As expected, sparkling, more dizzy
ドキ・ドキ・して Rouge?
Does your heart throb, Rouge?
あぁ、お許しくだた～い！このマリンの…
Ah, please forgive me~! This Marine's...
【魅力！魔力！不可抗力！】 罪な女ね？
【Charm! Magic! Force majeure!】 A sinful woman, right?
離さないで つかまっていて
Don't let go, hold on
世界の広さ 見せたげるから！ (出航!!)
Because I'll show you the vastness of the world! (Set sail!!)
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, pretty girl innocent
キミの一番目指してヨーソロー！
Aiming to be your number one, steady as she goes!
冗談も大好きだけど真剣よ
I love jokes too but I'm serious
きゅっ きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅっ きゅるんるん
Kyu kyu kyurun kyu kyu kyurun-run
恋する気持ち17歳
Feelings of love, 17 years old
0時(テッペン)になっちゃう オトナの時間
It's becoming midnight, adult time
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
As expected, sparkling, more dizzy
ドキ・ドキ・して Rouge? まだ早い♡
Does your heart throb, Rouge? It's still too early♡
(無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！)
(Innocent! Innocent! Pretty girl innocent!)
(マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！)
(Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!)
(やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ)
(As expected, sparkling, more dizzy)
「マリン」じゃなくて… 「マリン船長」だるぉぉぉん！！
Not "Marine"... it's "Captain Marine" right!!?
ピーマ様が来てくれましたー！ やったー！
P-ma-sama came to visit! Yay!
踊ってくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for dancing with me!
実はマリン、めちゃくちゃ好きなんですピーマ様が！
Actually Marine, I love P-ma-sama so much!
やったー！ (私も大好き！)
Yay! (I love you too!)
(私も大好き！)
(I love you too!)
いいの！？ テンションいいの！？
Is it okay!? Is this energy okay!?
ところでピーマ様、今日はね、マリンの誕生日なんです。
By the way P-ma-sama, today is Marine's birthday.
あ、おめでとう！
Ah, happy birthday!
17歳！ イエーイ！
17 years old! Yay!
え、本当は何歳？
Wait, how old are you really?
本当はー、ま、17から30の間を
In reality, well, somewhere between 17 and 30...
可変式にこう…行ったり来たりしてます。
I variably go back and forth like this.
私も！
Me too!
私もじゃないでしょｗ
Not 'me too' for you, right? lol
おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
ちょっとやっぱP丸様と歌うならと思ってね。
I thought, if I'm singing with P-maru-sama...
みんな大好きなシル・ヴ・プレジデント...言いにくい...
everyone's favorite "S'il Vous President"... it's hard to say...
シル・ヴ・プレジデント歌わせてもらいました！マジ最高！
I got to sing "S'il Vous President"! It was the best!
うわー！わしも美ショパイ大好きだから、嬉しい！
Whoa! I love "Bisho-pai" too, so I'm happy!
え、さっきのちょっとプチ裏話は話してもいいやつですか？
Um, is it okay to tell that little behind-the-scenes story from earlier?
あ、全然いいよ！
Oh, totally fine!
なんとP丸様、なんと美ショパイ「歌ってみた」を出そうとしていたらしいです！
Turns out P-maru-sama was actually planning to release a "Bisho-pai" cover!
そう！出そうかな？出そうかな？って思ってたけど...
Yeah! I was thinking "Should I? Should I?"...
何とも言え、今さら...
I don't know, it's kind of late now...
ちょっと遅くないか？遅いけど、
Isn't it a bit late? It is late, but...
でも丁度歌おうと思ってた時にマリンがお声がけしたみたいで。
But right when she was thinking of singing it, I reached out to her.
そう、ありがとうございます！
Yeah, thank you!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you as well!
あの、P丸様ってさ、いきなり呼び捨てみたいになってるけどこれ呼び方大丈夫そうですか？
Um, calling you "P-maru-sama" feels like I'm suddenly being too familiar, is this okay?
いいよ、いいよ！あ、いいですか？じゃあ何て...何て呼びます？マリンのこと。
It's fine, it's fine! / Oh, really? Then how... how should I call you? Or how do you call me?
マリン...ちゃん？ マリンちゃん！これ初絡み、初絡み。
Marine...-chan? / Marine-chan! This is our first interaction, first interaction.
そうなの、そうなの！
That's right, that's right!
え、何でも、なんかP丸に、マリンでも。
Uh, anything like P-maru, or Marine.
え、船長かな？ あ、船長、船長でいいですよ。
Maybe Senchou? / Ah, Senchou, Senchou is fine.
P丸様って、でも普段「Pちゃん」とか呼ばれてますよね。
But P-maru-sama, you're usually called "P-chan" and stuff, right?
呼ばれてるけど、まだちょっと、まだ仲良くないから、もうちょっと仲良くなりたい！
I am, but we're not... we're not that close yet, so I want to get closer first!
待って待って、ズキズキ...え、こよりとかとね、コラボしてましたよね。
Wait, wait, that hurts... Uh, you've collaborated with Koyori and others, right?
そう！ え、こよりのことは何て呼んでる？
Yeah! / What do you call Koyori?
こよりちゃん。
Koyori-chan.
こよりちゃん。え、仲いい？ え、仲いいと思ってるけど、こよりちゃんはどうかわかんない。
Koyori-chan. Are you close? / Well, I think we're close, but I don't know what Koyori-chan thinks.
あ、思ってる思ってる！こよりちゃん、ありがとう！
Oh, she does, she does! Koyori-chan, thank you!
いきなりちょっと待って、よそ見しないで今マリンのことだけ見て。
Wait a second, don't look away, just look at me right now.
あ、そうだった、そうだった。
Ah, right, right.
でかい。 でかい？え、何が何が？
Big. / Big? What is?
でかい！え、何これ、これこれこれ。
Big! What's this, this, this, this.
あ、ここね。あ、でもなんかこれくらいだよね。
Oh, here. But yours is about the same size, right?
は？おい！こんな感じだよね。
What? Hey! / It's like this, right?
いい、いい、ありがとう。こういうのがいいんだよ、結局なんだかんだね。
Fine, fine, thanks. This is what's good, after all.
でかいし小さい。
Big and small.
そうなの、小さいんです、意外と。
Yeah, I'm small, surprisingly.
かわいい！Pちゃんもかわいい！
Cute! P-chan is cute too!
ありがとう。え、こんな小さいんだ。
Thank you. Whoa, you're so small.
え、顔はでかいか。やめろ！顔はでかい！
Is my face big? / Stop it! My face is big!
顔でかい、胸でかい、背小さい。
Face big, chest big, height small.
顔...お前もでかいじゃねーか！
Face... yours is big too, isn't it?!
確かに！確かに！
True! True!
よかった、同じくらいの顔のデカさだから、バランスいいな、バランスいい！
Good, we have about the same face size, so it's balanced! Balanced!
また一緒に歌いたいな。
I want to sing with you again.
わしも！また一緒に歌おう。
Me too! Let's sing together again.
もっと仲良くなろうね、Pちゃん。
Let's get closer, P-chan.
なりましょう、マリン先輩。ちょっと、距離が、距離がすごいある！
Let's, Marine-senpai. / Wait, that distance, there's a huge distance there!
マリン先輩じゃなかった、Pちゃん。はい、Pちゃんね。
Not Marine-senpai, P-chan. / Yes, P-chan.
呼び捨てで、タメ口でいいので。 ありがとうございます！
You can drop the honorifics and speak casually. / Thank you very much!
さあ、もうね、ライブも終盤となっておりますので、
Well, the live is already in its final stages, so...
まだまだラストスパート盛り上がっていきたいと思います！
I want to keep the excitement going for the final spurt!
それではいきましょう。出航！ ヨーソロー！
Here we go. Set sail! Yosoro!
バイバーイ！ありがとうございます！
Bye-bye! Thank you very much!
わー！だんだん消えていく、だんだん消えていく。
Whoa! She's slowly disappearing, slowly disappearing.
Butter-Fly / 作詞・作曲 千綿偉功
Butter-Fly / Lyrics & Composition: Chiwata Hidenori
ゴキゲンな蝶になって　きらめく風に乗って
I'll become a happy butterfly, and ride on the glittering wind
今すぐ　キミに会いに行こう
I'll go to see you right now
余計な事なんて　忘れた方がマシさ
It's better to forget about the unnecessary things
これ以上　シャレてる時間はない
There's no more time to be stylish
何が WOW WOW～　この空に届くのだろう
What will reach this sky? WOW WOW...
だけど WOW WOW～　明日の予定もわからない
But WOW WOW... I don't even know tomorrow's plans
無限大な夢のあとの　何もない世の中じゃ
In this world with nothing left after our infinite dreams
そうさ愛しい　想いも負けそうになるけど
That's right, even my beloved feelings seem like they'll lose
Stayしがちなイメージだらけの　頼りない翼でも
Even with these unreliable wings, full of images of staying still
きっと飛べるさ On My Love
I'm sure I can fly, On My Love
ウカレタ蝶になって　一途な風に乗って
I'll become a cheerful butterfly, and ride on the single-minded wind
どこまでも　キミに会いに行こう
I'll go to see you anywhere
曖昧な言葉って　意外に便利だって
Vague words are surprisingly convenient
叫んでる...
shouting...
踏んでるヒットソング聴きながら
While listening to the hit songs we're stepping to
何が WOW WOW WOW WOW WOW この街に響くのだろう
What will "wow wow" through this city?
だけど WOW WOW WOW WOW WOW 期待してても仕方ない
But "wow wow", it's no use having expectations.
無限大な夢のあとの 何もない世の中じゃ
In this empty world after an infinite dream,
そうさ常識 はずれも悪くはないかな
Yeah, maybe being unconventional isn't so bad.
Stayしそうなイメージを染めた
Dyed with an image that seems to stay,
ぎこちない翼でも
even with these awkward wings.
きっと飛べるさ On my love
I'm sure I can fly, on my love.
無限大な夢のあとの 何もない世の中じゃ
In this empty world after an infinite dream,
そうさ愛おしい 想いも負けそうになるけど
Yeah, even my precious feelings seem like they'll lose,
Stayしがちなイメージだらけの
full of images that tend to stay,
頼りない翼でも
even with these unreliable wings.
きっと飛べるさ Oh yeah~
I'm sure I can fly, oh yeah~
無限大な夢のあとの やるせない世の中じゃ
In this miserable world after an infinite dream,
そうさ常識 はずれも悪くはないかな
Yeah, maybe being unconventional isn't so bad.
Stayしそうなイメージを染めた
Dyed with an image that seems to stay,
ぎこちない翼でも
even with these awkward wings.
きっと飛べるさ On my love
I'm sure I can fly, on my love.
特報
BREAKING NEWS
歌：宝鐘マリン
作詞・編曲：かめりあ(Camellia)
作曲：Toby Fox
Vocals: Houshou Marine
Lyrics/Arrangement: Camellia
Composition: Toby Fox
幽霊船戦
DEAD MA'AM'S CHEST
HOUSHOU MARINE
Dead Ma'am's Chest
DEAD MA'AM'S CHEST
HOUSHOU MARINE
このあとプレミア公開
Premiering after this
全国流通 1stアルバム 発売決定！
1st album major release confirmed!
Ahoy!! キミたちみんな全員パイレーツ
Ahoy!! You're All Pirates
さらに！アルバムに向けて豪華クリエイター陣が書き下ろした 新曲4曲を収録!!
Plus! Includes 4 brand-new songs written by a luxurious team of creators!!
2024 10.16 [Wed] RELEASE
私のもの そう私のもの 千の黄金
Mine, yes, it's mine, a thousand gold coins,
数百年の財宝 この船に眠る
treasures from centuries ago sleep in this ship.
幽霊船戦
作詞・編曲：かめりあ 作曲：Toby Fox
Dead Ma'am's Chest
Lyrics/Arrangement: Camellia, Composition: Toby Fox
古びた伝説は 呪われた幽霊船に
An old legend, on a cursed ghost ship
続く夜の航路
A continuing night voyage
そこに雷が遺る 海賊の夢があるのなら
If there's a pirate's dream where lightning remains
頂くしかないでしょ？
I'll have to take it, won't I?
「無謀な赤よ 若き盗人よ」
“Reckless red, young thief.”
「命をもって後悔に代えさせてやろう」
“I'll make you pay with your life in regret.”
止まない雨の弾丸で
With a rain of bullets that never stops
美しいほどこの身焦がす 生命の炎
A flame of life so beautiful it scorches this body
ガーネットの色彩
The colors of garnet
攫う宝石なのなら
If it's a jewel to be snatched away
私のもの そう私のもの 奪ってみろ
Mine, yes mine, try to steal it
命の証を 貴方の求める全てを
The proof of life, everything you seek
輝きはくすんで錆びついて
The radiance is dull and rusted
それでも泥舟にしがみつくなら
But if you still cling to the sinking ship
泡沫と共に沈め
Sink along with the bubbles
黒い帆に隠れる
Hiding behind black sails
極上の海賊の秘宝
The ultimate pirate treasure
掴んで笑う
Grab it and laugh
満月の金銀珠玉 七つの海の宝玉に
The gold and silver jewels of the full moon,
to the gems of the seven seas
「集まる虫ども」
“Gathering vermin”
こぞり雷を狙う 愚か者に思い知らす
I'll teach those fools who all target the lightning
相応しい持ち主を
Who the rightful owner is
船に宿る 黒い魂の群れ
A host of black souls dwelling in the ship
影の底で忍び寄る絶望の渦
A vortex of despair creeping at the
bottom of the shadows
まるで蓋の閉じた箱
Just like a box with its lid closed
手放しちゃえば 諦めちゃえば
If you just let go, if you just give up
悪夢の中から逃げられるのに また掴んでる
You could escape from the nightmare,
yet you're grasping again
欲望が重いから
Because your desires are heavy
「＊わたしのもの そうわたしのもの」
“*Mine, yes mine”
自分自身を信じ込ませて縛って
Convincing and binding yourself
縛り付けたてたって 気付いた
I realized I was tied down
呪いの出口 永久の夜の海域
The exit to the curse, the waters of eternal night
目を覚まして 貴方の悪夢から
Wake up from your nightmare
連れ出す曳き船よ 出航して
Oh towboat that leads me out, set sail
私のもの まだ私のもの 深紅のバラ
Mine, still mine, the crimson rose
朽ち果てたとしても
Even if it rots away
枯れない魂までは
Until the soul that never withers
万の由珠 永遠の美貌
Countless jewels, eternal beauty
そんな幻 どうだっていいでしょう
A phantom like that, who cares about it anyway?
手放す決意はついたかい
Have you made the resolve to let go?
さあ行こう 夜明けに舵を向けて
Now let's go, steer toward the dawn
曰くを宿した船 希望だけ残して行く
The ship that harbored a curse, I leave
with only hope remaining
他にはもういらないから
Because I don't need anything else anymore
君たち！生誕ライブをご覧いただきありがとうございました。
Everyone! Thank you for watching the birthday live.
本日お披露目した新曲「幽霊船戦」はこのあとミュージックビデオプレミア公開です！
The new song revealed today, 'Dead Ma'am's Chest',
will have its MV premiere right after this!
マリ箱からウン年後の世界、死んでしまったマリン船長のストーリーになっています。
It's a story of Captain Marine who died in the
world several years after 'Maribako'.
マリ箱開けてもらえなすぎて死んでしまった。
She died because people wouldn't open the
'Maribako' enough.
突然復活する幽霊船。壮大なバトルミュージックビデオになってるのでぜひご覧ください！
The ghost ship suddenly revives. It's an epic battle
MV, so please check it out!
24時からは各音楽サイトにて楽曲配信もありますよ。
The song will also be available on various music
streaming sites starting at midnight.
そしてこちらの「幽霊船戦」ですが、新宿駅東口のクロス新宿ビジョンでの放映が決定しました！
Also, for 'Dead Ma'am's Chest', a screening at
Cross Shinjuku Vision has been confirmed!
7月31日から8月6日まで15秒のスポットが、8月1日から15日まで90秒ミュージックビデオが流れますよ！
A 15-second spot will play from July 31st to Aug 6th,
and a 90-second MV from Aug 1st to the 15th!
ぜひご覧ください！そして配信内でも紹介しましたが、
Please take a look! Also, as I introduced
during the stream,
船長初の全国流通1stアルバム「Ahoy!! キミたちみんなパイレーツ」が今年2024年の10月16日にリリースします！
My first-ever nationwide 1st album, 'Ahoy!! You're
All Pirates', will be released on Oct 16th, 2024!
これまで出してきたオリジナル楽曲に加えて、4曲の新曲も入ってますよ！
In addition to previous original songs, it
includes four new songs!
どれも癖の...
They're all very...
新録楽曲ですので、超楽しみにしていてください！
It includes newly recorded tracks, so please look forward to them!
ホロライブオフィシャルショップ限定販売の数量限定盤は、パッケージも豪華な内容になっています。
The limited edition available only at the Hololive Official Shop has a luxurious package.
今までのミュージックビデオを収録したブルーレイに、アクリルスタンド、ポスター型の歌詞カード。
It includes a Blu-ray with music videos, an acrylic stand, and a poster-style lyric card.
さらに、ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの船長カードも収録しております。
Plus, a Captain card for the Hololive Official Card Game is included.
カードの詳細はホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームのXアカウントをフォローしてチェックしてください。
Check the Hololive Official Card Game's X account for details.
あかさあい先生描き下ろしのこちらの表情は、数量限定盤のみに収録。
This illustration by Akasa-ai-sensei is only included in the limited edition.
ご購入は先着順となっておりますので、お見逃しなく。
Purchases are first-come, first-served, so don't miss out.
続きまして、全国のCDショップで買える通常盤には、全4種類のランダムアナザージャケットが1枚付いてきます。
Next, the standard edition available at CD shops nationwide comes with one of four random 'another jackets'.
絵柄は後日公開するので、お楽しみに。
The designs will be revealed later, so look forward to it.
数量限定で、船長の直筆サインが入っているかもしれませんよ。
In limited quantities, there might even be a hand-signed autograph from the Captain!
さらにさらに、各店舗でアルバムを買ってくれた人には、店舗別特典が付きます。
Furthermore, those who buy the album at various stores will receive store-specific benefits.
お店ごとにたくさん種類があるので、ぜひチェックしてみてください。
There are many types for each store, so please check them out.
ファーストアルバム「Ahoy!! キミたちみんなパイレーツ」の情報は、アルバム特設サイトでも紹介しています。
Information on the 1st album "Ahoy!! You're All Pirates" is also available on the special site.
ハッシュタグは #キミパイ でお願いしますね。
Please use the hashtag #KimiPai.
さて、続いては誕生日記念グッズの告知をさせていただきます。
Now, I'll announce the birthday anniversary merchandise.
まずはこちら。お披露目したばかりの新衣装、部屋着のアクリルスタンドです。とっても可愛い！ぜひお部屋に置いてくださいね。
First is this. An acrylic stand of my newly revealed room-wear. So cute! Please display it in your room.
あかさあい先生描き下ろしとなっています。
It's illustrated by Akasa-ai-sensei.
そして続いては、船長の部屋着とお揃い、クマ耳クマ耳パーカーです。男性でも着やすい黒色。
Next is a bear-ear hoodie matching my room-wear. In black, which is easy for men to wear too.
船長とペアルック部屋着するために、ぜひ普段お部屋でも着てくださいね。
Please wear it at home to have a matching look with the Captain.
そんなにキャラグッズ感もないので、普段使いもしやすいのではないでしょうか。
It doesn't feel too much like character merch, so it should be easy for daily use.
そしてこちらは、船長がデザインした一味クマのぬいぐるみです。
And here is the Ichimi-kuma plushie designed by the Captain.
船長が自分の部屋にキミたちだと思って飾ろうと思って作りました。
I made it thinking I'd display it in my room as if it were you all.
とっても愛らしいし、船長の持っているものとお揃いなので、ぜひお迎えしてあげてくださいね。
It's very adorable and matches the one I have, so please take it home.
このピュアな瞳を無視できるか？
Can you ignore these pure eyes?
駄目押しでこちらの映像もご覧ください。
As a final push, please watch this video too.
キミたち、この愛らしいクマちゃんご覧ください！こちらはですね、船長が新衣装で、お部屋着の衣装でね、抱っこしているクマちゃんなんですが。
Everyone, look at this adorable bear! This is the bear I hold in my new room-wear outfit.
船長が一味だと思って、そして部屋に飾りたいと思うような、可愛い一味っぽいクマちゃんをね、デザインしました。
I designed a cute Ichimi-like bear that I'd want to display in my room, thinking of it as an Ichimi.
このクマちゃん船長もね部屋に置きたいなという可愛いクマちゃんだと思うので、船長が書いたんですよ。可愛いでしょ！
I think it's a cute bear that I'd want in my room too. I drew it myself! Isn't it cute?
ぜひともお揃いで、一緒に持ちましょう！ゲットしてください！
Let's have matching ones! Please get it!
購入お願いします。ほら、買って買って買って、買って買ってよ。
Please buy it. Look, buy it, buy it, buy it. Buy it, buy it!
お揃いで持とうよ。買ってくれないの？やだもん。
Let's have matching ones. Won't you buy it? No way.
もう買えよ！なあ、マリンが一生懸命考えたんじゃ。
Just buy it already! Marine worked so hard on this!
え、買ってくれるの？本当に？嬉しい！
Eh, you'll buy it? Really? I'm so happy!
キミのおうちに行けると思ったけど、いらないよね本当は。本当はいらないんだ。分かってんだから。
I thought I'd get to go to your house, but you don't really want it. You don't actually want it. I know that.
頑張って、頑張って、作った... 買って買って買って買え。
I worked so, so hard... Buy it, buy it, buy it, buy it!
ほら、クマちゃんをあなたのおうちに。あ、寝ちゃった。寝ちゃったみたい。ほら、母性溢れてきた。
Look, bring the bear to your home. Oh, he fell asleep. Seems like he fell asleep. My maternal instincts are kicking in.
ほら、よしよし。船長と一緒にこうやって、私たちの個よ。キミたち私たちの個よ。
There, there. Together with me, he's our child. You all, he's our child.
ほら、一緒に子育てするって約束したでしょ。
Look, you promised to raise a child with me, didn't you?
よし、怖いね、怖いね。よしよし。あ、ほらほら、一緒に帰ろうね。一味ちゃんのところと一緒に帰ろうね。
There, it's okay, it's okay. There, there. Look, let's go home together. Back to the Ichimi's place together.
はい、キミたちよろしくお願いします。イエーイ！抱っこ抱っこ！可愛いでしょ。
Yes, please take care of him. Yay! Cuddles! Isn't he cute?
さあ、そして全部セットをご購入の方には、直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードとお家デートボイスの特典が付いてきます。
And for those who buy the full set, you'll get a Polaroid-style bromide card with a handwritten message and a date-at-home voice benefit.
直筆メッセージは数量限定ですが、なくなり次第複製メッセージバージョンもありますので、そちらもぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
Handwritten messages are limited, but printed versions will be available after they run out, so please look forward to those too.
何気にこのチェキ風なの初めてなんで、ぜひゲットしてみてほしいです。こちらですごい可愛い表情になっていますのでよろしくお願いします。
Actually, this Polaroid-style one is a first, so I hope you get it. I have a very cute expression on it, so please check it out.
ということでキミたち、生誕祭祝ってくれてどうもありがとうございました。この後のプレミア公開見に行ってください。いいですか？
So everyone, thank you so much for celebrating my birthday festival. Please go watch the premiere after this. Got it?
それではいきますよ。出航！
Here we go. Depart!